{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "A detailed agreement between a client and a vendor describing the work to be performed on a project is referred to as:",
      "options": ["MSA", "SLA", "WO", "SOW"],
      "correct_answers": ["SOW"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refers to an analog telephone service providing basic voice communication over copper telephone lines?",
      "options": ["PSTN", "ISDN", "PBX", "POTS"],
      "correct_answers": ["POTS"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A protocol designed to improve the security of existing WEP implementations is known as:",
      "options": ["SRTP", "TKIP", "CCMP", "WPA2"],
      "correct_answers": ["TKIP"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the acronyms listed below refers to a technology used in cameras and surveillance systems that enables remote control of camera functions?",
      "options": ["RDP", "CCTV", "PTZ", "TCP/IP"],
      "correct_answers": ["PTZ"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following provides granular control over user access to specific network segments and resources based on their assigned roles and permissions?",
      "options": ["IAM", "SSO", "PAM", "MFA"],
      "correct_answers": ["IAM"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A security solution designed to detect anomalies in the log and event data collected from multiple network devices is called:",
      "options": ["SNMP", "PCAP", "HIPS", "SIEM"],
      "correct_answers": ["SIEM"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a smart card used in mobile phones to identify the phone user?",
      "options": ["IMSI", "SoC", "IMEI", "SIM"],
      "correct_answers": ["SIM"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following devices would be used for connecting a router to a T1 line?",
      "options": ["CSU", "IDF", "NIC", "EDR"],
      "correct_answers": ["CSU"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the applications of PGP? (Select 3 answers)",
      "options": ["Compressing data", "Encrypting and decrypting data", "Signing and verifying digital signatures", "Managing public and private keys", "Securing website traffic"],
      "correct_answers": ["Encrypting and decrypting data", "Signing and verifying digital signatures", "Managing public and private keys"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A field in an SSL/TLS certificate that allows the certificate to be used for multiple domain names or IP addresses is referred to as:",
      "options": ["CNAME", "SAN", "MX", "PTR"],
      "correct_answers": ["SAN"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a tunneling protocol commonly used in creating VPNs?",
      "options": ["VRRP", "GRE", "RTSP", "BGP"],
      "correct_answers": ["GRE"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refers to a professional that oversees the management and maintenance of an information repository?",
      "options": ["CTO", "PM", "DBA", "CIO"],
      "correct_answers": ["DBA"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the terms listed below refers to a US government initiative for real-time sharing of cyber threat indicators?",
      "options": ["NVD", "AIS", "TTP", "CVSS"],
      "correct_answers": ["AIS"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A type of OS characterized by low delay between the execution of tasks required in specific applications, such as in military missile guidance systems or in automotive braking systems, is known as:",
      "options": ["UNIX", "Windows NT", "POSIX", "RTOS"],
      "correct_answers": ["RTOS"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following block cipher modes is the simplest/weakest and therefore not recommended for use?",
      "options": ["CBC", "GCM", "ECB", "CTR"],
      "correct_answers": ["ECB"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which communication method supports real-time text-based messaging, multimedia sharing, group chats, and video calls?",
      "options": ["SMS", "MMS", "IM", "RTC"],
      "correct_answers": ["IM"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which senior executive position assumes the responsibility for protecting assets, data, and people from potential threats?",
      "options": ["CEO", "CIO", "CSO", "CTO"],
      "correct_answers": ["CSO"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which cybersecurity role is primarily responsible for hands-on implementation and oversight of security measures for specific systems and networks?",
      "options": ["CSO", "CTO", "DPO", "ISSO"],
      "correct_answers": ["ISSO"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A company or organization that offers cloud computing services over the Internet is called:",
      "options": ["ISP", "MSSP", "CSP", "MSP"],
      "correct_answers": ["CSP"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the terms listed below refers to a global community focused around the development of engineering standards?",
      "options": ["ANSI", "NIST", "CERT", "IEEE"],
      "correct_answers": ["IEEE"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refers to a device designed to supply (and monitor the quality of) electric power to multiple outlets?",
      "options": ["PSU", "MDF", "PDU", "IDF"],
      "correct_answers": ["PDU"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a global standard development organization composed of different national standards bodies?",
      "options": ["NIST", "ISO", "IEEE", "ANSI"],
      "correct_answers": ["ISO"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following acronyms refers to the process of identifying and preparing for potential disruptions or unexpected events to ensure business continuity?",
      "options": ["BIA", "SLE", "CP", "BPA"],
      "correct_answers": ["CP"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A dedicated local network consisting of devices providing data access is referred to as:",
      "options": ["SDN", "NAS", "iSCSI", "SAN"],
      "correct_answers": ["SAN"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which senior executive is responsible for managing an organization's IT strategy and systems?",
      "options": ["CEO", "CIO", "CSO", "CTO"],
      "correct_answers": ["CIO"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a framework used on Unix-like OSs to manage authentication-related tasks?",
      "options": ["PAM", "SSO", "MFA", "OAuth"],
      "correct_answers": ["PAM"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refers to a network protocol for delivering audio and video over IP networks?",
      "options": ["RDP", "VoIP", "RTP", "UDP"],
      "correct_answers": ["RTP"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the terms listed below refers to a specialized suite of software tools used for developing applications for a specific platform?",
      "options": ["GUI", "SDLC", "API", "SDK"],
      "correct_answers": ["SDK"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A type of software that serves as an intermediary between users and the hardware, allowing users to interact with the computer and run applications is known as:",
      "options": ["ROM", "BIOS", "OS", "RAM"],
      "correct_answers": ["OS"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refers to an encryption protocol primarily used in Wi-Fi networks implementing the WPA2 security standard?",
      "options": ["TKIP", "CCMP", "SSL", "HMAC"],
      "correct_answers": ["CCMP"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In telecommunications, a type of main hub connecting internal networks with outside cabling is called:",
      "options": ["MDF", "ICS", "MDI", "IDF"],
      "correct_answers": ["MDF"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the acronyms listed below refers to a protocol used in network management systems for monitoring network-attached devices?",
      "options": ["SSH", "VNC", "SNMP", "RDP"],
      "correct_answers": ["SNMP"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refers to a routing protocol?",
      "options": ["RTP", "BGP", "RDP", "EAP"],
      "correct_answers": ["BGP"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A specific URI type most commonly used to identify web pages is referred to as:",
      "options": ["DOI", "ISBN", "OUI", "URL"],
      "correct_answers": ["URL"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a solution that simplifies web browser configurations by using predefined rules or scripts to make server selection decisions for specific web traffic?",
      "options": ["PAC", "DDNS", "PAM", "NAT"],
      "correct_answers": ["PAC"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following terms refers to a network of physical devices, vehicles, buildings, and other items embedded with sensors, software, and other technologies that connect and exchange data with other devices and systems over the Internet?",
      "options": ["SoC", "PAN", "IoT", "WMN"],
      "correct_answers": ["IoT"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a unique 32-bit identifier embedded in older mobile phones and used by network operators to identify and authenticate the device on the cellular network?",
      "options": ["MAC", "ESN", "IP", "OID"],
      "correct_answers": ["ESN"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refers to a software-based solution that allows users to access and interact with a virtual OS from anywhere using any device with an Internet connection?",
      "options": ["VDU", "VTC", "VDE", "VNC"],
      "correct_answers": ["VDE"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the acronyms listed below refers to a broader term used to describe an organization responsible for responding to computer-related emergencies?",
      "options": ["CIRT", "CERN", "CERT", "CSIRT"],
      "correct_answers": ["CERT"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following acronyms refers to a discontinued research program focused on promoting innovation and development in the field of telecommunications and information technology?",
      "options": ["IETF", "CERN", "DARPA", "RACE"],
      "correct_answers": ["RACE"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a team of experts within an organization focused on responding to a wide variety of computer-related incidents?",
      "options": ["CERT", "CSIRT", "CIRT", "CERN"],
      "correct_answers": ["CIRT"]
    },
    {
      "question": "GPG is used for: (Select all that apply)",
      "options": ["Securing website traffic", "Managing public and private keys", "Signing and verifying digital signatures", "Compressing data", "Encrypting and decrypting data"],
      "correct_answers": ["Managing public and private keys", "Signing and verifying digital signatures", "Encrypting and decrypting data"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A software system that integrates and manages various business processes and functions across an organization is known as:",
      "options": ["BCP", "CMS", "ERP", "BIA"],
      "correct_answers": ["ERP"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is RIPEMD?",
      "options": ["Block cipher encryption mode", "Digital signature algorithm", "Family of cryptographic hash functions", "Symmetric encryption algorithm"],
      "correct_answers": ["Family of cryptographic hash functions"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following acronyms refers to a dedicated facility responsible for monitoring, detecting, investigating, and responding to cybersecurity incidents?",
      "options": ["NOC", "C2", "ISAC", "SOC"],
      "correct_answers": ["SOC"]
    }
  ]
}